<idea-plugin>
    <id>io.github.jacekgajek.koog-strategy-graph</id>
    <name>Koog Strategy Graph</name>
    <vendor email="jacek.s.gajek@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/jacekgajek">Jacek Gajek</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Visualization for <a href="https://github.com/JetBrains/koog">Koog</a>
        agent <code>strategy { ... }</code> DSL blocks.</p>
        <p>A gutter icon next to every recognized <code>strategy(...)</code> call
        renders the strategy as a Mermaid state diagram in the <em>Koog Strategy</em>
        tool window. The diagram is produced by Koog's own
        <code>MermaidDiagramGenerator</code>: the plugin lifts the
        <code>strategy { }</code> snippet into a temporary program, compiles it
        against your module, runs it, and displays the result &mdash; so the graph
        always matches Koog's real interpretation of the strategy. This requires the
        code to compile.</p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>0.1.7</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Compile failures are no longer shown as raw <code>kotlinc</code> diagnostics
                (whose temporary-directory paths looked like a plugin error). When the strategy
                can't compile because of <em>another</em> file — typically a stale or unbuilt
                dependency — the graph now shows a clear <em>"There are compile errors. Rebuild
                your project and refresh."</em> notice, where <em>refresh</em> is a link that
                re-generates the graph just like the toolbar button.</li>
            <li>Compile errors in the strategy's <em>own</em> file are no longer surfaced
                separately — you already see them in the editor. A previously rendered diagram
                stays on screen while you fix them; if there is no diagram yet, a brief
                "fix the compile errors" notice is shown instead of a stuck spinner.</li>
            <li>Errors no longer blank the canvas: while a valid diagram is on screen, a compile
                or graph error appears in an unobtrusive strip along the bottom, so live edits
                don't flip the view back and forth between the graph and an error message.</li>
            <li>Graph (strategy) errors and compile errors are now clearly distinguished, and the
                old "Graph problems" list was removed in favour of the single relevant message.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.6</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Node factories defined in a <em>separate file</em> (e.g. a helper
                <code>object</code>) are now supported: when the snippet-only compile can't
                resolve them — typically an unbuilt module — the referenced same-module
                sources are pulled into the compile, so the graph renders instead of failing.</li>
            <li>The compile's JVM target is now taken from the module's SDK, so strategies in
                modules whose dependencies target a newer JVM no longer fail with an
                <em>"cannot inline bytecode built with JVM target …"</em> error.</li>
            <li>Click-to-navigate and caret highlighting now follow node factories across
                files (including <code>Receiver.factory()</code> calls), jumping to the
                helper's declaration.</li>
            <li>Navigating to a node/edge no longer recenters the editor when the target line
                is already visible — it only scrolls when needed.</li>
            <li>A small, unobtrusive gray hourglass appears in the corner of the diagram while
                it is regenerating.</li>
            <li>Reformatting-only edits (whitespace, comments) no longer trigger a re-render;
                editing a same-file helper now does.</li>
            <li>Performance: graph generation and the PSI work behind caret highlighting and
                click navigation now run off the UI thread, so they no longer cause editor
                hangs or slow-operation warnings.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.5</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>The tool window now has an always-visible list of every <code>strategy { }</code>
                in the project (found via the IDE's index, so it's instant). Click a strategy to
                preview its graph beneath the list; double-click or press Enter to jump to its
                source, or use the right-click <em>Open in New Tab</em> to open it in its own
                pinned tab.</li>
            <li>Graph tabs can be detached into their own floating window (the <em>Detach to
                Window</em> toolbar button, or the list's right-click <em>Open in New Window</em>),
                so several strategies can be compared side by side.</li>
            <li>Added a refresh button to the tool window that re-generates the open graphs
                (and detached windows).</li>
            <li>Graphs (and the list) refresh automatically after a project build finishes,
                so they reflect freshly compiled module output.</li>
            <li>Reverse navigation: moving the editor caret onto a node declaration or an
                <code>edge(…)</code> highlights the matching node/edge in the graph — including
                subgraphs and edges inside them.</li>
            <li>Strategies that are members of a class with non-mockable constructor
                parameters (<code>String</code>, primitives) now render: those arguments get a
                literal default instead of a mock.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.4</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Strategies defined as members of a class, <code>object</code> or companion
                object are now supported: the class is instantiated with
                <code>mockk(relaxed = true)</code> per constructor parameter, so member
                helpers and injected dependencies resolve.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.3</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Fixed unresolved references to sibling files/declarations when rendering a
                strategy in a Gradle-delegated module: the module's compiled output
                directories are now added to the compile classpath and friend paths.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.2</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Graphs are now rendered with Koog's own <code>MermaidDiagramGenerator</code>:
                the <code>strategy { }</code> snippet is compiled against your module and run,
                so the diagram always matches Koog's real interpretation.</li>
            <li>Click a node to jump to its declaration, and click an edge (with a forgiving
                hit area) to jump to its <code>edge(from forwardTo to)</code> definition.</li>
            <li>The graph refreshes automatically as you edit, keeping the last valid diagram
                while the code is incomplete.</li>
            <li>Graph validation and compile errors are listed in a Problems-style panel
                without discarding the current diagram.</li>
            <li>Strategy tabs are pinnable and closable, like search results.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release: gutter icon + popup graph.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.kotlin</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <codeInsight.lineMarkerProvider
            language="kotlin"
            implementationClass="io.github.jacekgajek.koog.graph.marker.StrategyLineMarkerProvider"/>
        <toolWindow
            id="Koog Strategy"
            anchor="right"
            canCloseContents="true"
            icon="AllIcons.Toolwindows.ToolWindowHierarchy"
            factoryClass="io.github.jacekgajek.koog.graph.tool.KoogGraphToolWindowFactory"/>
    </extensions>

    <!-- Both K1 and K2 modes of the Kotlin plugin are supported. We walk syntactic
         PSI (KtCallExpression, KtProperty, KtBinaryExpression) and resolve plain PSI
         references (PsiReference.resolve), but never call the Analysis API — so the
         same code runs unchanged in either mode. Without this declaration K2 refuses
         to load the plugin. -->
    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="org.jetbrains.kotlin">
        <supportsKotlinPluginMode supportsK1="true" supportsK2="true"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
